اَعُوْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَّ الشِّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيْمِ۝
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمَانِ الرَّحِيْمَ۝
اَلْحَمْدُ لله وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد
وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تسليمًا كثيرا
The virtues of a Ash-Shuhadaa(ألشُهَدآء).
Ash-Shuhadaa(ألشُهَدآء) are blessed with many virtues from Allah,
some of which are,
and Ibn Nuhas(إبن نُحاس) I think mentions, how many does he mention?
Are they 19!
He has actually nine. Nine virtues!
The first one is to desire to die again for the sake of Allah.
No one; who enters paradise wants to leave it, even if they are given the world and everything on it,
with the exception of the Shaheed(شَهِيد).
He wants to leave paradise come back to this world and be killed in the sake of Allah again.
In Sahih Muslim(صحيح مسلم), the Messenger of Allah says;
No one, who enters paradise would want to go back to Earth but the Shaheed(شَهِيد),
he wants to go back to Earth in order to be killed for the sake of Allah 10 times.
That is when he sees what Allah has reserved for the Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء).
Rasool Allah ﷺ himself says in the name of whom Muhammad(محمد) soul in His hand,
I wish I could fight in the cause of Allah and then be killed,
and then fight and then be killed and then fight and then be killed.
Number two, forgiveness of all sins,
the moment the soul of the Shaheed(شَهِيد) leaves his body, it also leaves all his sins behind.
In Sahih Muslim(صحيح مسلم) Abu Qatadah(أبوقتادة) said:
Rasool Allah ﷺ delivered a Khut'ba(خطبة) and he said:
The Jihad(جهاد) in the path of Allah and Eeman(ايمان) are the greatest of all deeds.
So a man stood up and said:
O Rasool Ullah, if I am killed in the path of Allah, will that forgive my sins?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Yes, if you die with steadfastness and sincerity,
facing your enemy, and not turning your back to him.
The man asked again,
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Yes!
If you die was steadfastness and sincerity, facing your enemy and not turning your back to him.
And if you are not in debt.
مُقْبِلٌ غَيْرُ مُدْبِرٍ
Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) told me that.
So, the exception here is debt.
Abdullah Bin Amr Bin Al-Aas(عبدالله بن عَمْرُو بِن اَلْعَاص) narrated,
The Messenger of Allah said: The Shaheed(شَهِيد) is forgiven everything except debt
and this is in Muslim(ألمسلم) and In Al Hakim(ألحَاكِم) And Ahmad(أحمد).
So what does Al-Qurtubi(ألقرطبي) say about debt?
Al-Qurtubi(ألقرطبي) says:
the debt that is intended here, is when the Shaheed(شَهِيد) had the capability of paying it back,
but didn't or have the option of writing it in his will, and he didn't.
It would also include money that was borrowed for wasteful reason, and was not returned.
But when the Shaheed(شَهِيد) borrows money due to poverty and dire need,
and is then incapable of paying it back,
this would not withhold the Shaheed(شَهِيد) from Paradise.
In this case, the Sultan(سلطان) should pay back his debt,
if that didn't happen, then Allah Himself will pay it back for him.
As a Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
When you borrow and you sincerely want to pay it back, Allah will pay it for you.
And when you borrow money to waste, Allah will waste it.
And that's in Bukhari(بخاريْ).
So this point should be clear about debt.
If a person was in need, serious need, and they borrowed money they went to on Jihad(جهاد).
They couldn't pay it back before they go,
and they ended up dying Fee-Sabeel-Lillah(فِي سَبيل الله)
that's not gonna withhold them from Jannah(جنة).
But if somebody had enough money to buy a Honda Accord,
nevertheless, they wanted to buy a brand new BMW, and they borrowed money for that.
And they didn't pay it back.
That's a debt, that's unforgiving because, it's for a wasteful reason.
The Messenger of Allah said:
The Shaheed(شَهِيد) has seven qualities,
he would be forgiven with the first drop of his blood.
So just imagine that on the first drop of blood makes a touchdown,
all of the sins are gone,
Ahmad(أحمد) and Tabrani(طبراني).
Abdullah Bin Amr Bin Al-Aas(عبدالله بن عَمْرُو بِن اَلْعَاص) said:
When the servant is killed in the cause of Allah,
as soon as the first drop of his blood touches the ground, all of his sins are forgiven.
Number three,
the angels provide shade for the Shaheed(شَهِيد) with their wings.
Now, Allah Alam(ألله أعلم) if this, Yani(يعني) I believe that this is specific,
even though Ibn Nuhas(إبن نُحاس) mentioned it as something for all of the Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء)
but it might be specific to this particular case.
Jabir(جابر) narrated that his father was presented to the Messenger of Allah after his dead body was mutilated.
I wanted to uncover his face but some people told me not to.
We then heard some woman weeping so Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
Why are you weeping?
The angels are still providing shade for him up to this moment,
Allah Alam(ألله أعلم), this might be a special honor to the father of Jabir Bin Abdullah(جابر بن عبدالله).
Number four martyrdom, guarantees paradise.
Allah says:
إِنَّ اللَّهَ اشتَرىٰ مِنَ المُؤمِنينَ أَنفُسَهُم وَأَموالَهُم
وَأَموالَهُم بِأَنَّ لَهُمُ الجَنَّةَ ۚ
يُقاتِلونَ في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ فَيَقتُلونَ وَيُقتَلونَ
ۖ وَعدًا عَلَيهِ حَقًّا فِي التَّوراةِ وَالإِنجيلِ وَالقُرآنِ
ۚ وَمَن أَوفىٰ بِعَهدِهِ مِنَ اللَّهِ
ۚ فَاستَبشِروا بِبَيعِكُمُ الَّذي بايَعتُم بِهِ
ۚ وَذٰلِكَ هُوَ الفَوزُ العَظيمُ۞
Indeed Allah has purchased from the believers, their lives
and their properties and in exchange for that they will have paradise,
At-Toba(التوبة) Verse 111.
And Allah also says,
فَإِذا لَقيتُمُ الَّذينَ كَفَروا فَضَربَ الرِّقابِ حَتّىٰ إِذا أَثخَنتُموهُم فَشُدُّوا الوَثاقَ
فَإِمّا مَنًّا بَعدُ وَإِمّا فِداءً حَتّىٰ تَضَعَ الحَربُ أَوزارَها ۚ
ذٰلِكَ وَلَو يَشاءُ اللَّهُ لَانتَصَرَ مِنهُم
وَلٰكِن لِيَبلُوَ بَعضَكُم بِبَعضٍۗ
وَالَّذينَ قُتِلوا في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ فَلَن يُضِلَّ أَعمالَهُم۞
سَيَهديهِم وَيُصلِحُ بالَهُم ۞
وَيُدخِلُهُمُ الجَنَّةَ عَرَّفَها لَهُم ۞
And those who are killed in the cause of Allah.
Never will He waste their deeds.
He will guide them and amend their condition and admit them to paradise.
Muhammad(محمد), Verse four to six.
Samura Bin Jundab(سمرة بن جندب) narrated,
the Messenger of Allah said:
I've dreamed last night of two men who ascended with me and took me up to a tree
and we entered the mansion, I've never seen anything more beautiful than it.
They said: This mansion is for the Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء).
Abu Hurairah(ابوهريره) narrated the Messenger of Allah said:
Allah laughs at two men,
one of them kills the other and they both enter into paradise.
They said: How can that happen, O Messenger of Allah?
he said: One of them kills the other.
So the one who is killed goes to paradise, as a Shaheed(شَهِيد).
And then the one who killed him, embraces Islam
goes and fight in the path of Allah and is killed as a Shaheed(شَهِيد) and goes to paradise.
There's another Hadith(حديث) that when a Kafir(كافر) kills a Muslim,
and then that Kafir(كافر) and becomes a Muslim,
these two men end up loving each other so much in Jannah(جنة).
Because the Muslim knows that I got here because of you.
And the Kafir(كافر) says Al-hamdulillah(ألحمدلله) that guided me to Islam.
So, they end up having that close bond in Jannah(جنة).
Anas(أنس) narrated, the mother of Harisa(حارثه) came to Rasool Allah ﷺ and asked him:
O messenger of Allah! Won't you tell me about my son Harisa(حارثه),
if he is in paradise I would be patient and if he is not I would cry for him.
Harisa(حارثه) was killed during the Battle of Badr(بدر) by stray arrow, in a friendly fire.
So that's why his mother was worried.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Have you lost your mind.
أهابلتي
It is not one paradise, but many, and your son is in the highest one, Al-firdaus(ألفردوس).
Number five,
Their souls are in the inside of green birds in paradise.
Ibn Abbas(إبن عباس) narrated, the Messenger of Allah said:
When your brothers were killed at Uhud(أحَد),
Allah had their souls in the insides of green birds,
flying on the banks of the rivers of Paradise, and eating from the fruits thereof.
At night, these birds spend their evening in lanterns hanging to the throne of Allah.
So during the day, taking a tour of the rivers of Paradise,
the best beaches you could dream of, accrues on these beaches,
and then they spend the night under the throne of Allah.
When the martyrs saw the blessings they were in, they said,
who would convey to our brothers that we are living in Paradise,
so they won't ignore Jihad(جهاد) and stop fighting,
Allah than revealed.
وَلا تَحسَبَنَّ الَّذينَ قُتِلوا في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ أَمواتًا ۚ
بَل أَحياءٌ عِندَ رَبِّهِم يُرزَقونَ۞
So the whole purpose of the revelation of this Ayah(آية) was to fulfill the desire of these Shuhadaa(شهداء)
because people did not know yet that the Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء) were alive,
they did not know yet what the Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء) were going through.
So these Sahabah(صحابه) they wanted their brothers to know about what's happening.
So Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ revealed  the Ayaat(آيات) of Al-Imran(ألعمران), and Al-Baqarah(ألبقرة), which is talking about Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء).
And never think of those who have been killed in the cause of Allah as dead
rather they are alive with their Lord receiving provisions.
وَلا تَحسَبَنَّ الَّذينَ قُتِلوا في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ أَمواتًا ۚ
بَل أَحياءٌ عِندَ رَبِّهِم يُرزَقونَ۞
Rejoicing what Allah has bestowed on them of His bounty,
and they receive good tidings about those after them,
who have not yet joined them, that there will be no fear concerning them, nor will they grieve.
They receive good tidings of favor from Allah and bounty
and that Allah does not allow the reward of the believers to be lost.
And this is in Abu Daud(أبوداؤد) and Muslim(ألمسلم).
Number six,
They are not punished in their graves.
There is a Hadith(حديث) that states that the one who dies in Ribat(رباط)
would not be tested in their graves.
If this occurs to the one who dies in Ribat(رباط).
Then what about the one who dies as the Shaheed(شَهِيد).
The interrogation of the grave is meant to test the faith of a person.
Now if the Shaheed(شَهِيد) died fighting for the sake of Allah,
with swords flashing above his head, spears and arrows flying next to him,
and seeing heads and limbs being chopped off,
whoever sees that and then doesn't retreat, but rather fights until they die.
Giving up their soul for Allah is enough as a test for his faith.
So now you can replace the swords, spears and arrows with fire.
Number seven,
The Shaheed(شَهِيد) is spared from the shock of the blow of the horn.
Saeed Ibn Jubair(سعيد إبن جبير) was asked:
Who are the ones excluded by Allah  the following verse
and the horn will be blown and whoever is in the heavens and whoever is on earth will fall dead except whom Allah wills.
He said: They are the martyrs,
everyone else dies while they are surrounding the throne of Allah with their swords in their hands.
Now there's different views on who these are,
إلَّا ما شاء ربك
The ones who are excluded from this Ayah(آية).
Some say it's talking about Al-Malaikah(ألملائكة).
Some say it's talking about Al-Hoor Al-Ain(ألحورالعين) in Jannah(جنة).
And then you have this opinion here that it's a Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء), they are alive.
And this is in Ibn Al-Mubarik(أبن المبارك), Bukhari(بخاريْ) in Al-Kabir(ألكبير),
Abu Naeem(أبونعيم) At-Tabari(ألطبري) in his Tafseer(تفسير).
As-Sayuti(ألسيوطي) says it's authentic and Al Hakim(ألحَاكِم)  narrates it and Az-Zahbi(ألذهبي) authenticates it.
Rasool Allah ﷺ asked Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) about the ones who are excluded from the shock of the horn,
Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) said:
They are the martyrs,
Al Hakim(ألحَاكِم).
Number eight:
that's the mistake that should be number eight, that's Number 8
The Shaheed(شَهِيد) intercedes for 70 of his family.
Noman Bin Ut'ba(نعمان بن عُتْبَة) said: We went to visit on Um-Darda(أم درداء), and we were orphans
she said, rejoice.
I heard my husband Abu Darda(أبودرداء) say: Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
The Shaheed(شَهِيد) will intercede on behalf of 70 of his relatives.
Abu Daud(أبوداؤد), Ibn Haban(إبن حبان) and Al-Bayhaqi(ألبيهقي).
Now, this does not include friends, Is that clear?
It's just for family, this is for family not friends.
So we can only intercede for your family.
Your wives, your children, your parents, relatives.
Number 10:
The Shaheed(شَهِيد) feels peace on the Day of Judgment.
Nine, sorry. The Shaheed(شَهِيد) feels peace on the Day of Judgment.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said and he, the Shaheed(شَهِيد) feels peace at the time of the greatest fear.
Do you know, with the fear of the Day of Judgment.
It's so horrific.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says about it,
يومًا يجعل الولدان شيبا
It's a day that will make the child, gray headed.
And we recited the Ayah(آية) from Surat Ul Hajj(سورة الحَجْ),
يا أَيُّهَا النّاسُ اتَّقوا رَبَّكُم ۚ إِنَّ زَلزَلَةَ السّاعَةِ شَيءٌ عَظيمٌ۞
يَومَ تَرَونَها تَذهَلُ كُلُّ مُرضِعَةٍ عَمّا أَرضَعَت وَتَضَعُ كُلُّ ذاتِ حَملٍ حَملَها
وَتَضَعُ كُلُّ ذاتِ حَملٍ حَملَها وَتَرَى النّاسَ سُكارىٰ وَما هُم بِسُكارىٰ
وَما هُم بِسُكارىٰ وَلٰكِنَّ عَذابَ اللَّهِ شَديدٌ۞
إِنَّ زَلزَلَةَ السّاعَةِ شَيءٌ عَظيمٌ۞
That the shaking and the trials of the Day of Judgment is a huge affair.
يَومَ تَرَونَها تَذهَلُ كُلُّ مُرضِعَةٍ عَمّا أَرضَعَت وَتَضَعُ كُلُّ ذاتِ حَملٍ حَملَها
وَتَرَى النّاسَ سُكارىٰ وَما هُم بِسُكارىٰ وَلٰكِنَّ عَذابَ اللَّهِ شَديدٌ۞
The pregnant woman would have a miscarriage and you see people as if they're drunk,
but they're not drunk.
It is because of the terror of that day.
Now for Shaheed(شَهِيد) to be safe on that day,
for the Shaheed(شَهِيد) it was a few minutes and then he lost his soul.
And the result would be feeling safe on the Day of Judgment, which is 50,000 years long.
You see the Bedouin was very wise when he made the Dua(دُعَا).
اللهم اجعل خير أعمالنا خواتمها ، وخير أعمارنا أواخرها ، وخير أيامنا يوم ألقاك فيه،
There is a Bedouin who made the Dua(دُعَا), he said: Oh Allah!
I asked you to make the best of my deeds the last one.
And the best of my life, the end of it.
And the best of my day, is the day of judgment.
The day when I meet You.
See if you want to have the best day in your life, make sure that is the day of judgment
because that day is longer than your entire life in Duniyah(دُنِيَّا) multiplied by a 1000.
So, for a Shaheed(شَهِيد) to have peace on that day
and you know having peace on that day is such an important thing
that the Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ mentioned that this was Dua(دُعَا) of Eesa عليه السّلام.
وَالسَّلامُ عَلَيَّ يَومَ وُلِدتُ وَيَومَ أَموتُ وَيَومَ أُبعَثُ حَيًّا۞
Peace on them today was born the day he dies and the day is brought up again, which is the day of judgment.
The next one would be number 10.
The blood of the Shaheed(شَهِيد) doesn't dry until he sees his wives in paradise.
Abdullah Bin Obaidellah Bin Umair(عبدالله بن عبيدالله بن عمير) said:
When the two armies meet,
the women of Paradise descend to the lower heaven to watch the battle.
Halal(حلال) cheerleaders.
If they see a man steadfast,
they say: Oh, Allah him confirm.
While if he turns his back, they turn away from him.
So Yani(يعني),
if he's running away, they actually don't want to see that, he turn away.
If he is killed, they come down to him and wipe the dirt from his face.
That's Sahih(صحيح) narrated by Abdur Razzaq(عبدالرزاق).
In fact, it is quite a Mutawatir(متواتر) reference that
some Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء) not only see it when they're dying, but sometimes they see it even before that.
A brother was telling of, people whom he knows firsthand, and this is in Iraq,
in the North, Kurds.
The brother was sitting with, with his friends, and his eyes were fixed on something in front of him.
So the brothers were talking to him and he's not responding,
and they're trying to get his attention and he just his eyes are fixed.
And then after that, he sort of woke up he was daydreaming
and they asked him what's happening.?
He said: I was seeing in front of me, woman of Jannah(جنة), I was seeing Hur(حور) in front of me.
After he said that the missile landed right there and killed no one but him.
But it happened but he saw the Hur(حور) before he actually was going through the death process.
It was while he was still, Yani(يعني) nothing was happening.
And he was seeing the Hur(حور) when he was still awake.
This wasn't a dream, it was daydreaming.
So this is a contemporary story, and there are plenty of other stories in Afghanistan
all over you must have heard, many of them.
Of people actually seeing Al-Hur(ألحور) well in advance.
What number are we? Eleven,11.
The one who dies as a Shaheed(شَهِيد) is better than the one who wins and returns home safely.
Jabir(جابر) narrates the Messenger of Allah was asked about the best Jihad(جهاد).
He said;
The best Jihad(جهاد) is the one in which your horse is slain, and your blood is spilled.
I mention this Hadith(حديث) a few times before.
Amr Bin Absa(عمرو بن عبسة) narrates a man said:
O Messenger of Allah! What is Islam?
He said: Islam is the submission of your heart and that the Muslims are safe from your tongue and your hands.
He said: What is the best of Islam?
Rasool Allah ﷺ Eeman(ايمان).
He said: What is the Eeman(ايمان)?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: To believe in Allah, His angels, His books, His messengers,
and the resurrection after death.
He said: What is the best of Eeman(ايمان)?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said Hijrah(هجرة).
He said: What is Hijrah(هجرة)?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
أنت هجرة ومعاصي
That you leave things behind.
He said: What is the best of Hijrah(هجرة)?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Jihad(جهاد)!
He said: What is the best of Jihad(جهاد)?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: The one, whose horse is killed in his blood is spilled
and this is in Ahmad(أحمد), Tabrani(طبراني) and Al-Bahaqi(ألبيهقي).
Ibn Nuhas(إبن نُحاس) says;
These Ahadith(احاديث) are clear refutation of the claim that the one who wins is better than the one who is killed.
And that's why the Muslims in the Battle of Mu'tah(مَؤتَة) three thousand in front of 200,000
which is way more than one to two or even one to ten.
Because one to 10 would be 3000 against 30,000.
Here we have 200,000.
So I think it's about one to 60.
So the Sahabah(صحابه) said: Let's wait and send Rasool Allah ﷺ consult with him.
What should we do?
Either to come back or he will send some reinforcements for us
and that's when Abdullah Bin Rawaha(عبدالله بن رواحة) stood up
and he just inspired the whole army.
He said:
You want us to run away from what we have came here, in the first place.
The reason why we are here is to die, Shahadah(شَهَادَة) Fee-Sabeel-Lillah(فِي سَبيل الله).
And now you are you're asking us to retreat.
So that just inspired the whole army and they decided to go ahead and would fight.
So Shahadah(شَهَادَة) is greater than victory.
Abdullah Bin Obaidellah Bin Umair(عبدالله بن عبيدالله بن عمير) said,
Amr Bin Al-Aas(عَمْرُو بِن اَلْعَاص) was circling the Ka'aba(كعبه) when he passed by a circle of men from Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) sitting down.
When they saw him they asked each other who was better,
Amr Bin Al-Aas(عَمْرُو بِن اَلْعَاص) or his brother Hisham(هشام).
When Amr(عمرو) finished his Tawaf(طواف), he walked up to them and said:
I heard you say something about me, What was it?
They said;
We were wondering who's better you or your brother Hisham(هشام)?
Amr Bin Al-Aas(عَمْرُو بِن اَلْعَاص) said: I will tell you about that.
I was with my brother Hisham(هشام) at Yarmook(يرموك).
And we spent our night praying that Allah blesses us with martyrdom.
The next day my brother got it, but I didn't.
So you can see that he was better than me.
This is a statement from Amr(عمرو) that the one who is killed is better than the one who is not.
12,
the Shaheed(شَهِيد) does not feel the pain of death except like a brief sting.
Abu Hurairah(أبوهريرة) narrated Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
The Shaheed(شَهِيد) feels nothing from the agony of death
except like one of you would feel from a sting of an insect.
It's in At-Tirmidhi(ألتِّرمِذِيْ), An-Nasai(ألنَّسائ), Ibn Majah(إبن ماجه), Al-Bayhaqi(ألبيهقي) Al-Ahmad(ألأحمد), Ad-Darimi(ألدارمي).
In Majmo Al-Lataif(مجموع لطائف), it mentions that a man said:
Oh Allah, take my soul without me feeling any pain.
One day while he was walking in a farm, he felt tired, so he laid down to sleep.
Some non believers approached him and cut off his head.
One of his friends saw him in a dream and asked about him about himself.
He said, I slept in a farm and when I opened my eyes, I was in paradise.
He didn't feel anything.
Ibn Al-Mubarak(إبن المبارك) mentions a similar story about two Muslim prisoners of war,
they were threatened by the leader of the non believers to give up their religion.
When they refused, he threw them in a container that had oil boiling for three consecutive days.
Due to the extreme heat of the oil, shortly after they were thrown in it,
their bones stuck out from the surface.
Later on, their brother saw them in a dream and asked them about their condition.
They said:
It was only that first dip into the boiling oil, and then we went straight to Al-Firdaus(ألفردوس).
13,
you see, in your dealing with Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ for example, with Ibrahim عليه السّلام and Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل),
Allah told Ibrahim عليه السّلام to slaughter his son,
which is a very, very painful thing to do, extremely painful.
But the whole thing was a test from Allah.
So when Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) showed the willingness to do that,
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ not only spared him, the sacrifice of his son, but Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ ransomed his son.
And that remained as an event that we celebrate every year.
It is a Eid(عيد).
So, the event turned into a celebration in which we would always remember Ibrahim عليه السّلام and Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل).
And that's how it is, when you're dealing with Allah,
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ does not want you to suffer,
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ does not want you to go through difficulty, it is just a test.
So when somebody accepts the test and does something for Allah,
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ rewards them.
So, the Shaheed(شَهِيد) has put himself in a situation where potentially
he could suffer a lot of pain and suffering.
Because of that, Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ takes away all of the pain and suffering and gives Shaheed(شَهِيد) a pleasure.
While a person who stays away from the battlefield and stays away from Jihad(جهاد)
and stays away from the position of being a potential Shaheed(شَهِيد),
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ will make their lives miserable
and they end up suffering in Saqartul Moat(سكرات الموت)
and in the grave, and on the Day of Judgment, and in hellfire.
While the Shaheed(شَهِيد) is having a free ride throughout all of these stages.
Number 13, the angels continuously visit the martyrs and deliver their salaams to them.
Abdullah Bin Amr Bin Al-Aas(عبدالله بن عَمْرُو بِن اَلْعَاص) narrated the Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
The first company to enter Paradise are the poor Muhajireen(مهاجرين),
who protected this Ummah(امة) from harm.
When they hear they obey, one of them might need something from the sultan(سلطان), but he die without asking for it.
On the day of judgment, Allah will call paradise and it would come with all its beauty and splendor.
Allah will then say:
Where are my servants who fought in My cause and were killed or harmed and made Jihad(جهاد) for Me.
Let them enter into paradise without reckoning.
The angels will then come and prostrate to Allah and say:
Our Lord! We glorify you and praise you day and night.
Who are these people whom you preferred over us?
Allah will say these are the ones, who fought and were hurt in My cause.
The angels will then visit them from every gate say Salam(سلام) to you for your steadfastness.
What a best dwelling.
Ahmad(أحمد), Al Hakim(ألحَاكِم)  and authenticated byAz-Zahbi(ألذهبي).
14. Allah is pleased with the Shaheed(شَهِيد).
Anas رضي الله عنه narrated some men came to Rasool Allah ﷺ and asked him,
to send them 70 of the scholars of Qur'an, among whom was my uncle, Haram Bin Malhaan(حرام بن ملحان).
These men would recite and study Qur'an during the night, and during the day.
And they would fetch out water and bring it to the Masjid(مسجد),
they would go out logging and when they sell the wood,
they buy food for the poor in Masjid(مسجد).
So that was that was their life, they would pray at night.
And during the day, they would go and do some work.
They would eat from what their hands would reap
and they would also give whatever is left over to the Masakeen(مساكين) that was their daily life.
When Rasool Allah ﷺ send them to go and teach that tribe,
the tribesmen kill them all before they even reached to their destination.
After they were killed, they said: Oh Allah, convey to our Prophet
that we have met You and that You are pleased with us, and we are pleased with You.
My uncle was killed by a spear.
When he saw the spirit go through him.
The spear actually hit him from back,
Haram(حرام) he went to meet this chief of the tribe.
So the chief of the tribe gave a signal to kill Haram(حرام) from behind.
So Haram Bin Malhaan(حرام بن ملحان) was stabbed from his back and the Spear came out from the stomach.
So he saw the spear coming out.
And what was his response, when he saw the spirit coming out of his stomach?
He said:
فزت ورب الكعبه
I have won in the name of the Lord of Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه), I have won.
The Messenger of Allah said: Your brothers have been assassinated
and they have said O Allah convey to our Prophet that we have met You
and You are pleased with us and we are pleased with You.
One of the men, who were present when Haram(حرام) said:
فزت ورب الكعبه
That sentence kept on ringing in his head.
You know, How could you claim that you've won when you were killed?
And that led to his Islam? He couldn't forget that word.
And when he asked, he kept on asking you about it, he said:
Who are these people, and why are they doing that?
And that led him to Islam.
So not only did Haram(حرام), get Shahadah(شَهَادَة) but also somebody became Muslim because of it.
And Allah would laugh at both of them in paradise.
And this would be similar to the story of the young man in Sahih Muslim(صحيح مسلم).
He would studying under the sorcerer and the priest, his Shahadah(شَهَادَة), lead to the Islam of the people.
14) for martyrdom to be accepted, no good deeds are required to proceed it.
15) Al-Bara Bin Aazib(ألبراءبن عازب ) narrated the man covered in iron armor approach to the Messenger of Allah and said:
O Messenger of Allah should I fight or embrace Islam first,
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Embrace Islam and then fight.
He became a Muslim and fought and was killed.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: He did very little, but was rewarded a lot.
He did very little, and was rewarded a lot.
So tell that to the ones, who say we need to prepare our Eeman(ايمان)
and that preparation goes on for centuries and centuries and you're preparing your Eeman(ايمان).
And this man just became Muslim, and within a few minutes he was in Jannah(جنة).
Abu Musa Al-Ash'ari(أبوموسى ألأشعري) narrated Rasool Allah ﷺ was in battle
when one of the non believers asked for a duel.
A Muslim went up to him but was killed by the non believer.
He asked for another challenger, another Muslim went to him and was also killed.
Then the non believer came to Rasool Allah ﷺ asked him,
What are you fighting for?
So Rasool Allah ﷺ said: We fight people until they testify that there is no one worthy of worship other than Allah,
and that Muhammadﷺ is the Messenger of Allah, and that we fulfilled the rights of Allah.
The non believer said: What you said is admirable.
I accept that.
He then embraced Islam and turned to the side of the Muslims fighting with them.
He was later killed.
So he was carried and buried next to the same to Muslims he killed.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said in Paradise, there are no men who love each other more than these.
I mean, his sword is still dripping from their blood.
And he dies and get Shahadah(شَهَادَة).
This is Sahih(صحيح).
They love each other so much because the killed see the one, who kill them as the reason of blessing them with martyrdom.
Jabir Ibn Abdullah(جابر بن عبدالله) narrated,
we were with the Messenger of Allah during the Battle of Khaybar(خَيْبَر)
and he sent out a group of the army, who came back with a shepherd.
Rasool Allah ﷺ, spoke to the shepherd for a while.
Then, the man embraced Islam.
He asked Rasool Allah ﷺ, what should I do with these sheep?
They are entrusted to me and belong to other people and
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Take a handful of sand and throw it at them
and they will head back to their owners.
The man then joined the Muslims in their fight and was killed by an arrow.
He didn't have a chance to even pray one prayer.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told the companions to enter his body in his tent.
So they brought his body to the tent of Rasul Ullah.
They carried him to Rasool Allah ﷺ's tent and then Rasool Allah ﷺ came out saying;
Allah has accepted Islam,
when I went into the tent, I found him with two wives from Paradise.
16 Shaheed(شَهِيد) is married to Al-Hur(ألحور), Allah says:
وَحورٌ عينٌ۞ كَأَمثالِ اللُّؤلُؤِ المَكنونِ۞
جَزاءً بِما كانوا يَعمَلونَ۞
And for them are fair women with large beautiful eyes the likeliness of pearls well protected.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said in a Hadith(حديث) mentioning the virtues of the Shaheed(شَهِيد),
the Shaheed(شَهِيد) would be married to 72 of Al-Hur(ألحور).
And this is in At-Tirmidhi(ألتِّرمِذِيْ), Abdur Razzaq(عبدالرزاق) and Ibn Majah(إبن ماجه) and it is Hasan(حسن).
Rasool Allah ﷺ and if a woman of Paradise reveals herself to the people of this world,
she would fill the distance between them with light and scent
and the scarf on her head is better than the world and everything in it.
That’s in Bukhari(بخاريْ).
Abu Saeed Al-Khudri(أبوسعيدألخدري ) narrated the Messenger of Allah said:
A man would be reclining in paradise for 70 years before he moves.
Again, you remember the timeline, you are not in a hurry, just sitting down for 70 years.
Then a woman would come to him and pat on his shoulder.
He would look around and see her face.
Her face is so clear, he could see his image on her cheeks,
and one of her pearls would light the distance between the heavens and earth.
She would give him Salam(سلام).
He would then ask her who she is, she would say I am from Al-Mazeed(ألمزيد).
She would be dressed in 70 dresses, and he would still be able to see the marrow of her Shin from beneath the dresses.
That’s in Al-Ibn Habban(إبن حبَّان), Ahmad(أحمد), At-Tirmidhi(ألتِّرمِذِيْ), Abu-Ya'la(أبويعلي).
I'm sure you're quite impressed with this Huriya(حورية).
But let me tell you that no matter how hard you try to imagine how she looks,
it's not going to be a fraction of the real thing.
Al-Mazeed(ألمزيد) is mentioned in Qur'an Allah Promise the believers in paradise with Al-Mazeed(ألمزيد)
literally it means more.
So it could include any of the bonus rewards not mentioned in Qur'an and Sunnah(سنة).
You see in Jannah(جنة) a lot of things mentioned wasn't in Qur'an but there are many bonus things that are surprises.
That even when you're in Jannah(جنة) you don't know about them, they just suddenly show up.
It's a bonus thing that you get and you keep on getting these bonuses.
You never heard about them Qur'an and Sunnah(سنة),
it's just keep on dropping at you from time to time, to add to the excitement of Jannah(جنة).
Alright!
Chapter 13,
The rulings regarding Muslim P.O.W's.
By the way, Ibn Nuhas(إبن نُحاس), as far as I recall, in three to four places in the book.
You know, he would make this Dua(دُعَا), O Allah I ask you to give me Shahadah(شَهَادَة).
He's asking Allah to give him Shahadah(شَهَادَة).
He says it somewhere in the beginning of the book, he says that after the chapter on martyrs.
And he says it in a way, you know after you read everything about Shahadah(شَهَادَة)
and you're dreaming about all of that he just throws this Dua(دُعَا) in
and he says: O Allah I asked you to give me Shahadah(شَهَادَة).
And then he also does that as his last words in his book.
O Allah I asked you to give me Shahadah(شَهَادَة), that's his last statement in the book.
Two years after he finishes the book he dies as a Shaheed(شَهِيد).
So, it's a sign of Sidq(صدق).
Allah says,
وَما لَكُم لا تُقاتِلونَ في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ وَالمُستَضعَفينَ مِنَ الرِّجالِ وَالنِّساءِ وَالوِلدانِ الَّذينَ يَقولونَ
الَّذينَ يَقولونَ رَبَّنا أَخرِجنا مِن هٰذِهِ القَريَةِ الظّالِمِ أَهلُها
وَاجعَل لَنا مِن لَدُنكَ وَلِيًّا وَاجعَل لَنا مِن لَدُنكَ نَصيرًا۞
And what is the matter with you, that you fight not in the Cause of Allah
and for the oppressed, among men, women and children who say our Lord,
take us out of this city of oppressive people and appoint for us from Yourself a protector
and appoint for us from Yourself helper.
وَما لَكُم لا تُقاتِلونَ في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ وَالمُستَضعَفينَ مِنَ الرِّجالِ وَالنِّساءِ وَالوِلدانِ الَّذينَ
يَقولونَ رَبَّنا أَخرِجنا مِن هٰذِهِ القَريَةِ الظّالِمِ أَهلُها وَاجعَل لَنا مِن لَدُنكَ وَلِيًّا وَاجعَل لَنا مِن لَدُنكَ نَصيرًا۞
This is in surat An-Nisa(سورة النساء) Verse 75.
Al-Qurtubi(ألقرطبي) states in his Tafseer(تفسير) Allah has mandated Jihad(جهاد) in order to raise his word high,
and for his religion to prevail,
and to come to the rescue of the weak believers, even if that would lead to the loss of lives,
freeing the Muslim P.O.W's is mandatory, either through fighting or ransom.
Imam Malik(إمام مالك) says: Muslims need to free the P.O.W's, even if that would cost them all their wealth,
all their wealth.
And we're sitting on all of this cash and money, and we have just seen what our brothers are going through.
Now what they're going through, is for us.
They put themselves at risk they left their families behind they are in cage now, their business are wrecked.
They did it for the sake of the Ummah(امة).
So we owe it to them!
Abu Musa Al-Ash'ari(أبوموسى ألأشعري) narrated the Messenger of Allah said:
Free the P.O.W's, feed the hungry and visit the sick.
And this is in Bukhari(بخاريْ).
فك الآن
The Maz'hab(مذهب) of As-Shafie(ألشَّافعي) is that freeing the P.O.W's is recommended.
The Maz'hab(مذهب) of Imam Malik(اِمَام مالك) and Ahmad(أحمد) is that, it is compulsory.
If private money is paid to free the P.O.W's and it's permission was sought.
Then he needs to pay it back after he is freed.
If the money was paid without his knowledge,
there is a difference of opinion whether he should pay it back or not.
Umar Bin Abdulaziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز) stated that if a Muslim P.O.W asks for Muslims to pay for his release,
it is mandatory for Muslims to pay it.
Al-Qurtubi(ألقرطبي) says in the Tafseer(تفسير) of this verse.
إِنَّ الَّذينَ آمَنوا وَهاجَروا وَجاهَدوا بِأَموالِهِم وَأَنفُسِهِم في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ
وَالَّذينَ آوَوا وَنَصَروا أُولٰئِكَ بَعضُهُم أَولِياءُ بَعضٍ ۚ
وَالَّذينَ آمَنوا وَلَم يُهاجِروا ما لَكُم مِن وَلايَتِهِم مِن شَيءٍ حَتّىٰ يُهاجِروا ۚ
وَإِنِ استَنصَروكُم فِي الدّينِ فَعَلَيكُمُ النَّصرُ إِلّا
إِلّا عَلىٰ قَومٍ بَينَكُم وَبَينَهُم ميثاقٌ ۗ
وَاللَّهُ بِما تَعمَلونَ بَصيرٌ۞
But those who believed and did not immigrate for you there is no guardianship of them until they emigrated
and if they seek help, of you for the religion then you must help,
except against the people between yourselves and whom is a treaty.
And Allah is Seeing of that which you do
and this is in Al-Anfal(ألأنفال) Verse 72.
And then he says if the believers who did not emigrate from the land of the enemy,
asked the Muslims for help, whether in a military or financial form to release them.
It is mandatory on the Muslims to help, and it is prohibited to forsake them.
The only exception is if the Muslims are bound by an agreement with a non Muslim entity.
But this only holds if the withheld Muslims are not harmed.
If they are oppressed, then the Muslims need to help them.
Imam Abubakr Bin Arbi(إمام أبوبكربن عربي) says,
Except if the Muslims are oppressed in that case we need to secure their release until not a single eye among us blinks.
Which means, even if we all have to die for that.
You need to fight to release that Muslim, as long as there is an eye blinking among us.
As long as there's somebody alive.
That's how important it is.
And he says, it is also Qazi Abubakr Bin Arbi(قاضي أبوبكربن عربي), who said,
if a Muslim is held captive in the West, it becomes mandatory on the Muslims to free him, even the Muslims of the east.
These are the opinions of Imam Malik(إمام مالك) and all the other scholars.
How unfortunate it is to see today, our brothers left in the prisons of the enemy.
While our Treasuries are full of money, and we are full of strength.
Ibn Nuhas(إبن نُحاس) is talking about his time, but it also holds true today.
And brothers, when you're locked up in a small cell or in a cage and you speak to no one.
And if you're married, you're far away from your wife and your children for years.
And you just cut off from the entire world, just think how difficult that is.
Try to lock yourself up in a room for 24 hours.
And see how difficult it is, just the psychology psychological pain of it,
let alone the inconvenience of the toilet facilities the food that you're eating, the temperature,
everything else you know it's not, it's not comfortable at all.
Umar Bin Abdulaziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز) sent a letter to the Muslim POW's is in Constantinople.
He told them!
And Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) this is a Khalifah(خليفه) that had Taqwa(تقوى) and he cared for the Muslims.
You know when he became Khalifah(خليفه).
As soon as Baiyah(بَيْعة) was given to him when he came down from the Mimbar(ممبر).
He sat down and he told his scribe to come and the first order that he that he gives,
you know and some people were joking about that they said he's, he's very excited that he has became Khalifah(خليفه),
he is so excited, he can't even wait to get to the office.
Just came down from the Mimber(ممبر) in the Masjid(مسجد) and he is immediately, giving commands.
The first command was, to recall the army of Muslims, that was laying siege to Constantinople.
Even though this was a Jihad(جهاد) Fee-Sabeel-Lillah(فِي سَبيل الله) against the capital of the Byzantine Empire.
But the thing is that it was becoming personal.
The Khalifah(خليفه) before him was becoming so stubborn about it.
He wanted that seige to continue even though it was taken away the lives of hundreds of Muslims,
who are dying because of hunger and cold weather, and out of stubbornness, he said carry on that siege.
Umar Bin Abdulaziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز) said: Bring that army back.
Why are the Muslims killing themselves.?
So he calls that army back.
So Umar Bin Abdulaziz(عمربن عبدالعزيز) had this feeling for the Muslims, he would feel for the Muslim on the street, man or woman.
He sent this letter to the Muslim prisoners of war in Constantinople.
He told them you consider yourselves to be prisoners of war, you are not, you are locked in the Cause of Allah,
you are locked in cause of Allah.
I would like you to know that what whenever I give something to the Muslims I give more to your families.
And I'm sending so and so with five dinars for each one of you.
And if it wasn't that I fear the Roman dictator would take it from you.
I would have sent the more,
I have also sent so and so to secure the release of every single one of you, regardless of what the cost would be.
So rejoice and Assalam-O-Alaikum.
That's how he cared for his subjects.
Whatever it takes to free I'm going to pay.
And now Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), I don't know if I mentioned to you this story or not
one of my relatives told me about in another town in Yemen, he used to live there.
He said: He personally knows, wives of some of the Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء),
who would go begging from door to door begging for clothes for their children,
second hand clothes for them to put on Eid(عيد).
He personally knows that he's not talking about something he heard,
he said he knows these wives of Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء) widows, they would go knocking on the doors,
begging for second hand clothes to give to their kids on Eid(عيد).
Government is not doing anything for them, no relief organization is doing anything for them.
And that's how we pay back,
that's how the Ummah(امة) is paying back the Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء) who gave their lives for the honor of the Ummah(امة).
How could we go to sleep and how could we enjoy our food.
When some of the widows of Ash-Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء) are begging for secondhand clothes for their children.
And you know, brothers, think about how difficult it is, for a woman,
an honorable woman, a woman of dignity that never would do this never would beg,
how difficult it is to go and knock, just imagine if your wife has to go and knock on the doors of your friend's houses,
begging for secondhand clothes for your kids.
So this is a betrayal, this is this is treason.
If we allow this to happen in the Ummah(امة), while our pockets are full.
An-Nawwawi(ألنووِي) considers that the ruling on freeing the POW's
is similar to the ruling on the enemy invading a Muslim land.
So it becomes Fardh-Ain(فرض عين).
In fact he considers freeing the POW's is to be more of a priority,
because the sanctity of the Muslim soul is greater than that of the Muslim land.
In fact Rasool Allah ﷺ says that Hurma Damma Muslim(حرمة دم المسلم) is greater in sanctity than the house of Allah.
An example of that is when a Muslim woman, who was a POW with the Romans,
in Amuriya(عمورية) was slapped in the face by a Roman.
She then said:
وا معتصما
Al-Motasim(ألمعتصم) was the Muslim Khalifah(خليفه), she called his name.
When this was related to Al-Motasim(ألمعتصم) he sent an entire army to free her.
The Crusaders took 500 Muslim POW's in Ar-Rohaa(ألروحة).
So, the Sultan Emad-Ud-Din Zinki(سلطان عمادالدين زنكي ) conquered the town.
I think it's Ar-Rohaa(ألروحة).
He conquered the town and he released all of his POW's.
When Salahudin(صلاح الدين) won against the Crusaders in Hattein(حتين),
he released 20,000 Muslim prisoners of war from the Crusaders.
That was the state of the Muslim Mujahideen(مجاهدين) leaders.
They would train Muslim POW's, while taking prisoners from their enemy,
and then many of these non-believing POW's would embraces Islam, and ended up fighting with the Muslims.
These are the ones meant by the Messenger of Allah in his Hadith(حديث) mentioned in Bukhari(بخاريْ),
Allah is amazed with people who enter paradise in chains.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says that some people will enter paradise in chains.
Ibn Nuhas(إبن نُحاس) says: Which means that some non believers are brought in chains as POW's,
and then they believed in Allah, so it is as if these chains brought them to Islam.
So they were taken as prisoners of war chained.
That was the reason that guided them to Islams,
so on the Day of Judgment, they would be taken to Jannah(جنة) in chains, because that's how they entered into Islam.
The next chapter is on the history of Jihad(جهاد).
Imam Abu Abdullah Al-Halimi(إمام أبوعبدالله ألحليمي), in his book Shuab Al-Eeman(شعب الايمان) he says:
The Prophet ﷺ had different stages with the non believers before Jihad(جهاد) was prescribed.
It began with the revelation of recite in the Name of your Lord, Who created, Al-Alaq(ألعلق).
Number two,
then Allah instructed him to convey His message, Oh you covered himself arise and warn,
يا أَيُّهَا المُدَّثِّرُ۞ قُم فَأَنذِر۞
So now he's going through the stages of Da'wah(دعوة).
Number three,
when he conveyed the message and they belied him, Allah commanded him to be patient with them.
وَاصبِر عَلىٰ ما يَقولونَ وَاهجُرهُم هَجرًا جَميلًا۞
And be patient over what they say and avoid them with gracious avoidance.
That is Muzamil(مزمل) Verse 10.
Then number four,
When a base was provided in Madina, Allah commanded the believers to make Hijrah(هجرة), from Makkah to Madina.
وَمَن يُهاجِر في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ يَجِد فِي الأَرضِ مُراغَمًا كَثيرًا وَسَعَةً ۚ
وَمَن يَخرُج مِن بَيتِهِ مُهاجِرًا إِلَى اللَّهِ وَرَسولِهِ ثُمَّ يُدرِكهُ المَوتُ
ثُمَّ يُدرِكهُ المَوتُ فَقَد وَقَعَ أَجرُهُ عَلَى اللَّهِ ۗ
وَكانَ اللَّهُ غَفورًا رَحيمًا۞
And whoever emigrates for the cause of Allah will find on the earth many alternative locations and abundance.
An-Nisa(ألنساء) Verse 100.
Number five,
When they made Hijrah(هجرة), they were given permission to fight.
أُذِنَ لِلَّذينَ يُقاتَلونَ بِأَنَّهُم ظُلِموا ۚ وَإِنَّ اللَّهَ عَلىٰ نَصرِهِم لَقَديرٌ۞
Permission to fight has been given to those who are being fought
because they were wronged and indeed, Allah is competent to give them victory.
Number six,
then they were instructed to fight whoever fights them.
وَقاتِلوا في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ الَّذينَ يُقاتِلونَكُم وَلا تَعتَدوا ۚ
إِنَّ اللَّهَ لا يُحِبُّ المُعتَدينَ۞
Fight in the way of Allah, those who fight you, but do not transgress.
وَقاتِلوا في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ الَّذينَ يُقاتِلونَكُم وَلا تَعتَدوا ۚ إِنَّ اللَّهَ لا يُحِبُّ المُعتَدينَ۞
Indeed Allah does not like the transgressors.
And that's in Al-Baqarah(ألبقرة) Verse 190.
Stage number seven,
They were later on order to fight all the non believers surrounding them.
يا أَيُّهَا الَّذينَ آمَنوا قاتِلُوا الَّذينَ يَلونَكُم مِنَ الكُفّارِ وَليَجِدوا فيكُم غِلظَةً ۚ
وَاعلَموا أَنَّ اللَّهَ مَعَ المُتَّقينَ۞
Oh you, who have believed, fight those adjacent to you of the disbelievers, and let them find in you harshness
and know that Allah is with the righteous,
and this is in At-Toba(التوبة) verse 123.
يا أَيُّهَا الَّذينَ آمَنوا قاتِلُوا الَّذينَ يَلونَكُم مِنَ الكُفّارِ وَليَجِدوا فيكُم غِلظَةً ۚ
Allah told them let fighting is prescribed on them and is compulsory,
كُتِبَ عَلَيكُمُ القِتالُ وَهُوَ كُرهٌ لَكُم ۖ وَعَسىٰ أَن تَكرَهوا شَيئًا وَهُوَ خَيرٌ لَكُم ۖ
Oh you who have believed, Fighting has been enjoined upon you, while it is hateful to you,
but perhaps you hate the thing, and it is good for you, and perhaps you love a thing and it's bad for you.
And Allah knows while you know not.
Allah also told them that fighting is a covenant between them and Allah.
And that's the Ayah(آية),
إِنَّ اللَّهَ اشتَرىٰ مِنَ المُؤمِنينَ أَنفُسَهُم وَأَموالَهُم بِأَنَّ لَهُمُ الجَنَّةَ ۚ
And then he also says,
So when Allah prescribed Jihad(جهاد), accepting it, and following it became part and its parcel of Eeman(ايمان).
The contract is that whoever kills the non believers is rewarded with paradise
and whomever the non believers kill is rewarded with paradise.
You kill the non believers, you go to paradise, you are killed by the non believers you go to paradise.
If you accept this contract, and you wanted paradise, then you must fulfill your part of the agreement,
and that is giving your soul and wealth to Allah.
And then he says: The value of the merchandise is dependent on three elements.
Number one, the buyer.
A noble buyer would only buy valuable merchandise.
You know, what is the most expensive shopping center in this country?
Harrods.
There's a dissenting view over here.
Okay Harrods.
When you go to Harrods, do you find homeless people shopping.?
Do you find the rank and file shopping or you would find the high class shopping in Harrods.
So, the nobel buyers and the wealthy, they would only buy valuable stuff, stuff has to have value.
Number two the salesman.
A noble salesman would not negotiate an invaluable sale.
Noble salesman will not negotiate an invaluable sale.
The salesman will only look for what is worthy.
Number three, the price,
an expensive price is not paid for worthless merchandise.
I cannot sell you this cookie for 100 pounds,
but I can sell you this mini disc player for 100 pounds.
So there needs to be some value.
So what is the item.?
It says the believer's soul,
so that's the item,
look at the value of Allah put on your soul.
He is the buyer.
Muhammadﷺ is the salesman,
and the price is paradise.
That is the greatest honor for the believers.
The only condition Allah placed on receiving the price, paradise
is for you to fight in the cause of Allah with your soul, and your wealth.
They fight in the Cause of Allah so they kill, and are killed.
Allah even recorded the contract for you a true promise,
the contract is recorded in the three books, Qur'an, Torah(توراة) and Injeel(أنجيل).
Allah says:
A true promise binding upon him in the Torah(توراة) and the Gospel and Qur'an.
So, the contract is not documented once, but there are three documents, Al-Quran(ألقرآن), gospel and Torah(توراة).
Scholars differed on the exact number of battles, the Messenger of Allah, went out.
In Muslim(ألمسلم) Jabir(جابر) states, the Messenger of Allah fought in 21 battles.
Zaid(زيد) mentions 19, while Ibn Is'haq(إبن إسحاق) mentioned, 27.
You have in Seerah(سيرة) something called Ghazwa(غزوة), and you have something called Sariyah(سرية).
What's the difference between the two.?
There's Ghazwa(غزوة) and there's Sariyah(سرية).
Linguistically Ghazwa(غزوة) means to attack or raid, that is Ghazwa(غزوة).
And Sariyah(سرية) means detachment.
So what's the difference between the two? Ghazwa(غزوة) and Sariyah(سرية).
Yes
Okay, which one is which.
Okay, Ghazwa(غزوة) is the one Rasool Allah ﷺ went with.
Do we call Mu'tah(مَؤتَة) Ghazwa(غزوة) or Sariyah(سرية)?
You need to answer that
No it's called Ghazwa(غزوة)
The answer is right!
Ghazwa(غزوة) is when Rasool Allah ﷺ goes out is called Ghazwa(غزوة)
and Sariyah(سرية) when he doesn't go out.
But how come Ghazwa Mu'tah(غزوة مَؤتَة) is called Ghazwa(غزوة) when Rasool Ullah didn't go out?
No!
Alright!
this was, yes!
That was Usama Bin Zaid(أسامه بن زيد)'s one, which was a consequence of the Mu'tah(مَؤتَة).
The reason why Mu'tah(مَؤتَة) is called Ghazwa(غزوة), is because
it's given this title as an exception is because,
Ghazwa Mu'tah(غزوة مَؤتَة), was such a great and important event so it was elevated to the status a Ghazwa(غزوة).
That's the reason, it was elevated to a status of as Ghazwa(غزوة), because of the importance of it.
This was the first confrontation between the Muslims and Ahlal Al-Kitab(أهل الكتاب) Ar-Rome(أللروم),
and it was a large army of 3000 and great events happen there in.
So, it is referred to in all of the books of history as a Ghazwa(غزوة) and not as Sariyah(سرية).
Sariyah(سرية) is tends to be smaller in size.
And mostly they were raiding armies led by Sahabah رضي الله عنهم as part of the economical warfare, led by Rasool Allah ﷺ.
While that Ghazwaat(غزوات), In Sha Allah(إنْ شاءالله) we'll go through them
and we'll just then read a list of the Sarayah(سراية) of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Number one, Al-Abwa(ألأبواء),
and there's not enough time to go through every one of them
in fact, Ibn Nuhas(إبن نُحاس) himself doesn't really elaborate much on them.
Sometimes he just mentions, the title of the Ghazwa(غزوة).
But Al-Abwa(ألأبواء) number one, this occurred in Safar(صفر), in the first year of Hijrah(هجرة) and no fighting occurred.
Number two Buaat(بوات), this happened in Rabi-Ul-Awal(ربيع الأول), second year of Hijrah(هجرة).
Number three, Al-Asheerah(ألعشيرة), and this happened in Jumada Al-Ula(جمادى ألأولى) second year of Hijrah.
And then you have the first battle of Badr(بدر) and this occurred a few days after Al-Asheerah(ألعشيرة).
And then you have the major battle of Badr(بدر),
Ibn Nuhas(إبن نُحاس) says this was the great battle which honored Islam and humiliated the infidels.
It was one of the greatest days for the Muslims.
It occurred, the morning of the 17th of Ramadan(رمضان), second year of Hijrah(هجرة).
So this was one of the battles of Ramadan(رمضان),
by the way the month of Ramadan(رمضان) is the month of Jihad(جهاد), that's when Badr(بدر) occurred,
Fath-E-Makkah(فتح مكه), Ain-Jalut(عين جالوت).
A little over 310 Sahabah(صحابه) participated in it.
And Wallah Ho Alam(ولله أعلم) the number of Sahabah(صحابه) who participate in the Battle of Badr(بدر)
is the same number of fighters that fight with Talut(طالوت).
Al-Bara'a(ألبراء) said: The Sahabah(صحابه), of the Messenger of Allah told me
that the number of Muslims in the Battle of Badr(بدر) was the same number of fighters in the army of Talut(طالوت).
Now the enemy was 1000 strong.
When Rasool Allah ﷺ heard of the caravan carrying a huge amount of wealth, belonging to Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
He encourages his Sahabah(صحابه) to confiscate it.
They missed the caravan but ended up meeting an army of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) that rushed to the defense of the caravan.
The battle started with three men of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) fighting one on one
with Hamza(حمزه), Ali(علي), and Ubaidah Bin Haris(عبيدة بن حارث).
All three men of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) were killed.
Rasool Allah ﷺ then straighten the ranks of the army.
He was walking in front of the ranks with a piece of wood in his hand.
Rasool Allah ﷺ was straightening the ranks, wanted the ranks to be straight, and nobody protruding out of these ranks.
Because Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ says,
إِنَّ اللَّهَ يُحِبُّ الَّذينَ يُقاتِلونَ في سَبيلِهِ صَفًّا كَأَنَّهُم بُنيانٌ مَرصوصٌ۞
As if they are, Bunyaan Marsoos(بُنيانٌ مَرصوصٌ), as if they are a wall.
So, Sawad Bin Ghuzaiyyah(سوادبن غزية) one of the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم was a step ahead of the rest.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ pushed him in the stomach and told him,
إستو يا سواد
Sawad(سواد) said: O Rasool Allah ﷺ you hurt me.
So I want to, to get even with you.
Just imagine the Sahabah(صحابه) hearing that,
he want to get even with Rasool Allah ﷺ.
But Rasool Allah ﷺ very calmly, he said:
Go ahead and he uncovered his stomach Rasul Ullah uncovered his stomach for Sawad(سواد).
Rasool Allah ﷺ was the leader, the Nabi(نَبِي) of Allah, he could have disciplined Sawad(سواد)
asking to get even with Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And then Sawad(سواد), he just jumped on Rasool Allah ﷺ hugged him and kissed his stomach.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told him.
يا سواد ما حملك على ما صنعتك
O sawad(سواد), why did he do that.
He said:
لقد حضر ما ترى من القتال
O messenger of Allah you see what we are going to face and this might be the last day in my life.
So I wanted my last moments to be my skin, touching yours.
I wanted my last moments to be my skin, touching yours.
That's the whole point why he wanted to get even with the Rasool Allah ﷺ.
So, that he could hug it Rasul Ullah and kiss him,
Rasool Allah ﷺ went aside and started supplicating, he said:
Oh Allah, if you allow this band to be destroyed, you won't be worshipped after this day.
There are no Muslims on the face of the earth except these, if they die, you are not going to be worshipped.
Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) said: Enough of asking Allah, Allah has promised you and will fulfill His promise.
Rasool Allah ﷺ a little later said: Rejoice, Abu Bakr(ابوبكر)!
أبشر يا أبا بكر
The victory of Allah is near.
Here comes Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل), riding his horse.
Allah says about that day:
إِذ يوحي رَبُّكَ إِلَى المَلائِكَةِ أَنّي مَعَكُم فَثَبِّتُوا الَّذينَ آمَنوا ۚ
سَأُلقي في قُلوبِ الَّذينَ كَفَرُوا الرُّعبَ فَاضرِبوا فَوقَ الأَعناقِ وَاضرِبوا مِنهُم كُلَّ بَنانٍ۞
Remember when your Lord inspired his angels, I am with you, so strengthen those who have believed,
I will cast her into the hearts of those who disbelieved,
so strike upon the necks and strike from them every fingertip.
This is in Al-Anfal(أنفال) Verse 12.
And this Hadith(حديث) is in Bukhari(بخاريْ).
إِذ يوحي رَبُّكَ إِلَى المَلائِكَةِ أَنّي مَعَكُم فَثَبِّتُوا الَّذينَ آمَنوا ۚ سَأُلقي في قُلوبِ الَّذينَ كَفَرُوا الرُّعبَ
فَاضرِبوا فَوقَ الأَعناقِ وَاضرِبوا مِنهُم كُلَّ بَنانٍ۞
Strike on their necks, strike their fingertips, which are holding the swords.
The battle was joined by 5000 Angels led by Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) himself.
Rifa'a(رفاعة) narrated Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) came to the Messenger of Allah and told him.
What do you consider the people of Badr(بدر) to be among you?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: We considered them to be the best.
Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) said;
And so we the angels consider the angels who attended Badr(بدر) to be the best among us.
So Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) wasn't only in an event of this world but it was a universal event.
The best of angels are the angels who attended the Battle of Badr(بدر),
so it is an event that is witnessed by the creation of the heavens
because, you know,
if you go and read the encyclopedias of war of the history of the world you might not come across the Battle of the Badr(بدر).
Kuffar(كفار), they don't even know what Badr(بدر) is, but that doesn't really mean anything.
But the angels know what Badr(بدر) is.
And the classification of the angels is based on the participation of Badr(بدر).
So it was an event that was witnessed by As-Saliheen(ألصالحين), and by the angels, and by a Shayateen(شياطين),
they were very displeased with the results.
70 of the infidels were killed and 70 were taken prisoners.
Allah says:
وَلَقَد نَصَرَكُمُ اللَّهُ بِبَدرٍ وَأَنتُم أَذِلَّةٌ ۖ
فَاتَّقُوا اللَّهَ لَعَلَّكُم تَشكُرونَ۞
And already had Allah, given you victory at Badr(بدر) while you were weak.
Then fear Allah, perhaps you would be grateful.
Al-Imran(ألعمران) Verse 123.
Number six, Banu Sulaim(بنوسُلَيم).
Seven days after returning from Badr(بدر) Rasool Allah ﷺ attacked Banu Sulaim(بنوسُلَيم), but no fighting occurred.
He camped in their land for three days and then returned to Madina.
Number seven,
Banu Qainqah(بنوقينقاع),
Banu Qainqah(بنوقينقاع) is the first conflict between the Muslims and the Jews.
Rasool Allah ﷺ, after the Battle of Badr(بدر) went to the Jews in their marketplace.
And he said: You know that I'm the Messenger of Allah so follow me.
Otherwise the fate of the Mushrikeen(مشركين) will befall you.
What did Banu Qainqah(بنوقينقاع) say?
They said: Don't boast about that victory because you have met people who have no experience in fighting.
If you meet us, you'll know who the real men are.
There was a Muslim woman in their marketplace.
She was fixing some gold jewelry of her.
And they asked her to uncover her face,
they wanted to take a look at her face she refused.
So one of them sneak behind her, she was sitting on a chair
and he hooked her, bottom of her Jilbab(جلباب) to her back.
So, obviously when you're setting your clothes drag, they're loose.
So, without her feelings, he just picked up the tip of it and stuck it to her back.
So once she stood up what happened, her private parts were uncovered.
So she screamed a Muslim saw this, and he jumped at the Jew, who did that and killed him.
The Jews jumped at him and killed him.
And that's when Rasool Allah ﷺ considered that the agreement between him and them is broken.
Rasool Allah ﷺ attack them in their fortresses and these men who claim that they're going to fight like men.
Didn't even fire one shot, not even one shot,
they just broke down and they said: And they didn't even negotiate the terms they just gave up.
Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن اُبَيئ) was their ally because Banu Qainqah(بنوقينقاع) were the allies of Al-khazraj(ألخزرج).
There were two Arab tribes in Madina, Al-Khazraj(ألخزرج) and Al-Aos(ألأوس), they were fighting each other.
And they had alliances with the Jewish tribes, who would support them with weapons sell them weapons.
So, Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن اُبَيئ) came to Rasool Allah ﷺ and said,
أحسن في موالي
Take care of my allies, Rasool Ullah ignored him.
Take care of my allies, Rasool Ullah is ignoring him.
Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن اُبَيئ) felt that Rasool Allah ﷺ might have the execution on mind.
So he went to Rasool Ullah and he stuck his hand in his pocket
and he pulled Rasool Allah ﷺ and Rasool Ullah was very upset
and he said;
أرسلني
Let me go.!
Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن اُبَيئ) said: I will not, until you are kind, with my allies,
Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
ويحك أرسلني
Woe to you! Leave me alone!
He said: I'm not gonna let you go, these are 700 men, who protected me from the white and the black,
meaning they fought with me on different occasions, and you want to kill them in one day.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
هم لك
They are yours, take them.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ gave them to Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن اُبَيئ).
They were allowed to leave.
However, their weapons were taken and obviously they had to give up their land and their houses.
So they left!
This was the first confrontation between Rasool Allah ﷺ and Yahood(يهود).
Ghazwa Suwaik(غزوة السويك), Number eight
On the fifth of Zul-Hijjah(ذوالحجة), second year of Hijrah(هجرة),
Rasool Allah ﷺ left Madina in pursuit of a caravan of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) led by Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان).
When Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان) learned of that, he escaped that's why no fighting occurred.
Number nine, Ghatafan(غطافان),
it happened in the land of Najd(نجد) Rabi-Ul-Awwal(ربيع الأول) third year of Hijrah(هجرة).
Rasool Allah ﷺ led an army of 450 but no fighting occurred.
Number 10.
The second Ghazwa(غزوة) of Banu Sulaim(بنوسُليم).
Rasool Allah ﷺ attacked the land of Banu Sulaim(بنوسُليم), but for a second time, the enemy did not come out to fight.
Rasool Allah ﷺ stayed in their land for two months.
Number 11, Uhud(أحَد),
it happened in Shawal(شوال), third year of Hijrah(هجرة).
Muslim army was 700, the enemy was 3000.
The Muslims started out as 1000 but Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن اُبَيئ) broke off with 300.
The banner of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) was entrusted to the family of Abu Talha(أبوطلحة),
before the battle started the banner was with the Talha Bin Abi Talha(طلحة بن أبي طلحة), he asked for a duel.
So Ali(علي) went to face him and killed him.
The banner was then carried by his brother Uthman(عثمان), who was killed by Hamza(حمزه),
then his brother Saad(سعد) carried it and it was killed by Saad Bin Abi Waqas(سعدبن أبي وقاص)
then it was carried by Abu Talha(أبوطلحة), grandson Musafah(مصافحه), who was killed by Asim Bin Sabith(عاصم بن ثابت).
Then it was carried by his brother, Kulaab(كلاب).
Who was killed by Zubair Bin Awam(زبيربن عوام),
then it was carried by his brother Jallas(جلَّاس), who was in turn killed by Talha Bin Ubaid-Illah(طلحة بن عبيدالله)
then it was carried by the relatives of Sharhabil Bin Arta'a(شرحبيل بن أرطعة), and was killed by Ali(علي),
the banner was then left on the ground after seven men from the same family were killed.
By the way this family of Bannu Abd-Ad-Dar(بنوعبدألدار), they also are the ones who hold the key to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
And they still hold it, until this day, it's their descendents, they're the ones who hold the key to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
When the banner fell down with it came the defeat of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and they began their retreat,
but because the archers on the mountain disobeyed the clear orders of the Messenger of Allah and left their post,
Khalid Ibn Walid(خالد ابن وليد) and Ikrama Bin Abi Jahl(عكرمةبن أبي جهل), took advantage of that
and ambushed the Muslims who thought the battle was over,
it was in the Battle of Uhud(أحَد) that Hamza(حمزه), the uncle of Rasool Allah ﷺ was killed.
He is the greatest of the Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء).
The day of Uhud(أحَد) was a trial for the Muslims.
Ibn Al-Qayyim(إبن ألقيم), Interesting enough, he considers Uhud(أحَد) to be a victory.
Traditionally, it is considered to be loss, but he considers it to be a victory because he said:
Uhud(أحَد) is a gold mine of lessons.
About 80 Ayaat(آيات) of Surat-Al-Imran(سورة ألعمران) are commenting on the battle of Uhud(أحَد).
And in his book on Seerah(سيرة), he would go on and on and on for pages
just talking about what the Muslims have learned from the experience of Uhud(أحَد),
what happens to you when you disobey.
Can Muslims lose in a battle.
That was also in the Ayah(آية) was revealed but if Rasool Allah ﷺ is killed, would you retreat back on your heels,
and that was the Ayah(آية) that Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) quoted when Rasool Allah ﷺ died.
Many, many lessons are learned. It was also,
وَيَتَّخِذَ مِنكُم شُهَداءَ ۗ
The Ayaat(آيات) of Shahadah(شَهَادَة) were revealed talking about Uhud(أحَد).
And Allah says that He chooses Shuhadaa(شُهَدآء) among you,
Rasool Allah ﷺ part of his genius, as a leader.
No matter what happens, no matter what happens, Rasool Allah ﷺ would never lose hope.
Rasool Allah ﷺ had that ability of inspiring the Muslims, even immediately after the defeat,
so right after the defeat Rasool Allah ﷺ is taking the same army, the same army, and he is pursuing the army of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
they just lost, Rasool Allah ﷺ mobilize them again and said: Let's attack.
It was Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) that ran away Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), who won the war, ran away.
And this Ghazwa(غزوة) was called Hamra Al-Asad(حمراء ألأسد)
it occurred on Sunday, the 16th of Shawal(شوال) third year of Hijrah(هجرة), immediately following Uhud(أحَد),
Rasool Allah ﷺ mobilized the Muslims to go out and chase the army of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
to show to them that even though they lost Uhud(أحَد), they are still capable of fighting.
When Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان) heard of the move of the Muslims, he hasten to Makkah to avoid combat.
No fighting occurred.
If Banu Qainqah(بنوقينقاع) occurred after Badr(بدر), Banu Nadhir(بنونضير) occurred after Uhud(أحَد),
what happened five months after Uhud(أحَد), in Rabi-Ul-Awwal(ربيع ألأول) the fourth year of Hijrah(هجرة).
This was a Jewish tribe in Madina, that broke its agreement with the Messenger of Allah.
So he attacked them and laid siege to their powerful fortress.
What happened, how come they broke their promise with Rasool Allah ﷺ, Banu Nadhir(بنونضير)?
What happened with Banu Nadhir(بنونضير)?
Banu Nadhir(بنونضير) is the second Jewish tribe to vacate Madina.
There was a man called Amr Bin Umayah Ad-Damri(عمروبن أمية ألضمري).
He became Muslim, but this man in his Jahiliyyah(جَاهلِيَّة) was an assassin, a paid assassin.
You pay him money, he takes care of your opponent.
So, in Islam, he continued with his profession, although he did it in a Halal(حلال) way.
Sometimes he would kill some unintended targets.
He gave Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) a hard time, he gave Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) a hard time.
But what happened was,
there was this tribe in Najd(نجد) that killed the Sahabah(صحابه) of Rasool Ullah, the Qur'a(قرَّاة).
So, Amr Bin Umayah(عمروبن أمية ) saw these two men and he would just go around Arabia traveling.
He saw these two men he said: Where are you from?
They said: We're from Banu Amir(بنوعامر).
He said: Alright these are from Banu Amir(بنوعامر).
Banu Amir(بنوعامر) are the tribe that betrayed the Qura'a(قرّاة), Huffaz(حفَّاظ) of Qur'an.
The thing is that these specific two men had a peace agreement with Rasul Ullah.
So Amr Bin Umayah(عمروبن أمية) just waited until they slept, then he beheaded both of them.
And he came to Rasool Allah ﷺ giving him the good news.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: What have you done.?
These men have an agreement with me.
والله لأدينَّهما
I'm gonna pay their blood money.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: I am gonna pay their blood money.
So, Rasool Ullah went to Banu Nadhir(بنونضير).
Because, there was an agreement between the Rasool Allah ﷺ and the Jewish tribes that they share in such burdens,
they share in blood money.
And number two, Banu Nadhir(بنونضير) were also allies of Banu Amir(بنوعامر).
So they have to contribute some money, into the Diyah(ديعة).
So Rasool Allah ﷺ and some of the Sahabah(صحابه), they went to visit Banu Nadhir(بنونضير).
They went to their fortresses which were outside Madina,
and Rasool Allah ﷺ told the Jews, we have to pay the blood money of these two men.
So, I want you to share the expenses.
They said: Abu Qasim(أبوقاسم), we're going to share with you, just give us a few moments, we'll go and get the money.
And they met him with a very smiling and welcoming face.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ was sitting under this wall.
The Jews they went and they said: Listen you're never gonna have a better opportunity to assassinate this man.
He is right here among our fortresses, let's get rid of him.
Whose gonna volunteer for that.
So one of their miserable men, volunteered for that.
So he picked up this mill, millstone, heavy stone, and he wanted to throw it from the top of the wall on Muhammadﷺ,
Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) came to Muhammadﷺ and told him about it,
Rasool Allah ﷺ and told him about it, Rasool Allah ﷺ stood up and left without telling the Sahabah(صحابه) anything.
He just walked away.
So the Sahabah(صحابه) waiting, waiting, waiting, waiting.
Rasool Ullah did not come back and Rasool Ullah didn't tell them where is he gonna go.
They assume that he's going to respond to the call of nature.
So after a long time, they started walking towards Madina,
and they saw somebody coming out, they said: where is Rasool Allah ﷺ?
He said: He's been in Madina for a long time now.
So they went to Rasool Ullah and they said what happened?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) came to me and said:
They wanted to kill me,
so Rasool Allah ﷺ mobilized the Muslim army, and they went to Banu Nadhir(بنونضير).
And Rasool Allah ﷺ, told them, give up! Submit!
So they refused. Well in the beginning they were willing they were willing to surrender.
However, Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن اُبَيئ), who was also an ally of Banu Nadhir(بنونضير),
he went to them and said:
If there's any fighting that's going to happen.
We will help you out, we will fight with you.
And if you are going to be driven out of your land, We're not going to allow that to happen, so stay put.
So Banu Nadhir(بنونضير) told Muhammadﷺ we're not gonna surrender.
Rasool Allah ﷺ laid siege to them and they were very wealthy and rich.
They had this vast land of palm groves, and they had some very powerful fortresses more than one.
They were counting on surviving a lot of siege because they have some good storage facilities, plus their farms outside.
But what Rasool Allah ﷺ started doing is, cutting down their palm trees, they started screaming,
يا محمد كنت تنها عن الفساد في الأرض والآن تفسد في الأرض
O Muhammad(محمد), you are preventing people from causing corruption in land and then you do it, yourself.
So Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ reveals the entire Surah(سورة) of Al-hashr(ألحشر), talking about Gazwat Nadhir(غزوةالنضير).
ما قَطَعتُم مِن لينَةٍ أَو تَرَكتُموها قائِمَةً عَلىٰ أُصولِها فَبِإِذنِ اللَّهِ وَلِيُخزِيَ الفاسِقينَ۞
Whatever tree that you have cut down or left.
It is by the permission of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ and it is to humiliate the disbelievers, and they surrendered.
Now Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ says, also about them.
وَظَنّوا أَنَّهُم مانِعَتُهُم حُصونُهُم مِنَ اللَّهِ
They thought that their fortresses, are going to protect them from Allah.
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ says,
وَقَذَفَ في قُلوبِهِمُ الرُّعبَ ۚ
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ cast fear in their hearts,
Brothers!
This is a powerful weapon that Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ uses against the enemies of Islam.
Sometimes you think about it in terms of numbers and equipment,
and you forget that there's this soldier of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ which is fear,
When Allah puts that fear inside the heart of the enemy, no matter where the enemy is, no matter how strong they are,
no matter how well protected they are, if their hearts failed them, they're gone, that's it, it's the end of them.
So, Banu Nadhir(بنونضير) they have these powerful fortresses, they have good storage facilities, they have it all.
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ put fear in their hearts they couldn't carry on.
They just gave up.
And they came to Rasool Allah ﷺ and they said: We surrender.
So never under estimate the power of fear.
Specially, especially when the enemy of Allah hears Allah O Akbar.
You know, this story of one of the brother, he is contemporary Al-Bara Bin Malik(ألبراء بن مالك).
He jumped into Russian Camp, he Just went at night on his own to fight.
He took permission from Ameer(أمير), I am going there, he is an army on his own.
He just goes, he knows where the Russian camp is, it's under this cliff, this small mountain.
So he jumps from this cliff and lands on the camp, Booom!!
They just hear that sound of some body is landing there.
And they were sleep.
By the time they woke up and they picked up their arms
and just regain consciousness after hearing the Takbeer(تكبير) of this man.
Almost all of them were dead.
And what he did, Allah Alam(ألله أعلم), I mean something that shouldn't have been done.
But he cut the ears in the bag and took it back, he said: See, this is how many.
These are the enemies of Allah, it's how many of enemies of Allah that I got.
But that's a mutilation that's not allowed.
But anyways, the Takbeer(تكبير), Allah Ho Akbar(الله أكبر) but it just it causes, in some people, what is called Al-Akal(عكل).
Aqal(عكل) is when your body becomes paralyzed because of fear.
The body paralyzes the body cannot move.
The person has consciousness, but they lose control of the body.
Take a break for questions and after that few minute break.
Then we carry on with Ghazawaat(غزوات)
Any questions!
Question From Audience!
وَقاتِلوا في سَبيلِ اللَّهِ الَّذينَ يُقاتِلونَكُم وَلا تَعتَدوا ۚ
Allah does not like the transgressors.
Al-Baqarah(ألبقرة) Verse190.
It's very emotional for you as a Muslim to hear and see about such things
let alone an nonbeliever, who doesn't even understand where you're coming from, it's going to be astonishing.
I mean, for example, I remember this photo that was in the Shaql Al-Aosaq(شكل الأوسق) in Arabic Newspaper,
when they have these trials for Jamat-Uj-Jihad(جماعت الجهاد) in Egypt.
And guy took the photo straight after the sentence was announced at these men in the cage are all to be executed,
he just captured that photo at that moment.
When you look at their faces, lighting, and shining, smiling from ear to ear.
I just had to cut out that photo and just keep it.
They were so happy, they were so happy that they are gonna die.
Show that image to just like I was saying my conversation with this Yahoodi(يهودي).
He said: I don't get, I can't understand,
How come you don't love this life, Like we did?
crop the audio after this